Guide to the War Effort Mobilization Campaigns Poster Collection, 1942-1945 RL.01342
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
War Effort Mobilization Campaigns Poster collection
1942-1945
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
RL.01342
3 Linear Feet
240 Items
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. There may be a 48-hour delay in obtaining these materials.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The War Effort Mobilization Campaigns Poster Collection was received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a transfer in 1996.
Historical Note
Advertising campaigns that supported the war effort were designed by the War Advertising Council and approved by appropriate U. S. government agencies during World War II. Actual advertisements were in turn sponsored by various businesses which would often add the company name to the ads. Although it appears that the Outdoor Advertising Association of America played some role in the sale or distribution of billboard advertisements, that role within the context of this collection is unclear.
Collection Overview
The War Effort Mobilization Campaigns Poster Collection spans the years 1942-1945 and contains miniature reproductions of billboards designed by the War Advertising Council that advertise various government campaigns during World War II. A broad range of campaigns are represented in this collection, including war bonds, civilian employment, women’s Naval Reserve (WAVES) service, food rationing, civil defense, and fire prevention. Campaigns were approved by various government agencies. The Treasury Department is the most heavily represented agency in this collection, but other agencies such as the Office of Civilian Defense, the War Food Administration, the War Manpower (or Man Power) Commission, the National Housing Administration, and the Office of War Information are also included. Most of the posters are in full color and feature images depicting scenes involving military activity, civilian and family life, women’s war contributions, and patriotic symbolism. Many of the posters come with attached promotional literature or form part of sales kits designed to encourage businesses to purchase and sponsor a billboard to promote war effort campaigns in their community.
Included in the collection are examples of outdoor advertising for the Second through the Seventh War Loan drives. Examples of advertising for the First Bond drive (which was primarily promoted through newspapers and radio advertising) and the Eighth War Loan campaign may be found in the Ad*Access collection on the Web.
The War Effort Mobilization Campaigns collection consists of two series. The H.E. Fisk War Poster Collection Series contains war effort posters collected in a scrapbook by H.E. Fisk, an executive of the Outdoor Advertising Association of America (OAAA). The War Effort Sample Posters Series contains a wide range of war effort posters. There is some overlap between the two series.
Related materials may also be found in the R.C. Maxwell Company Records, the Outdoor Advertising Association of America Archives, the J. Walter Thompson Co. Archives: World War II Advertising Collection, and the Advertising Council Records. For additional information on advertising campaigns during World War II, please see http://scriptorium.lib.duke.edu/adaccess/wwad-history.html for an article titled "Brief History of World War II Advertising Campaigns." This article, part of the Ad*Access on-line image database, highlights six major advertising initiatives including the conservation, V-mail, and war bond campaigns.
World War, 1939-1945 -- Food supply -- United States; United States. Dept. of the Treasury; United States. Office of Civilian Defense; Savings bonds -- United States -- History; Advertising, Outdoor -- United States -- History; World War, 1939-1945 -- United States -- Posters; World War, 1939-1945 -- United States; World War, 1939-1945 -- Finance -- United States; World War, 1939-1945 -- United States -- Propaganda; Billboards -- United States -- History; World War, 1939-1945 -- War work -- United States; World War, 1939-1945 -- Women -- United States; Rationing -- United States -- History -- 20th century; War Advertising Council; Civil defense -- United States; Posters, American; United States. Office of War Information; Fisk, H. E.; United States. Naval Reserve. Women's Reserve; United States. War Manpower Commission; United States. War Food Administration; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; Outdoor Advertising Association of America; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; War Advertising Council
- H.E. Fisk War Poster Collection Series, 1942-1945, 3 boxes
  Scope and Contents note
  H. E. Fisk was the Executive Vice President of the Outdoor Advertising Association of America (OAAA) during World War II, and maintained a scrapbook collection of sample billboards that were used to sell war advertising to businesses.
  Arranged alphabetically by the government agency or other client represented in the advertisements, and thereunder by the design number that was printed on the verso of most posters. Unnumbered posters are listed at the end of each group, and are noted as being unnumbered. If there is more than one unnumbered design poster at the end of a group, they are arranged chronologically.
  - Christmas Designs (Box 1)
    - Design No. 319, Service Flag, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      [Brighten His Christmas - Send Your Gifts Early]
    - Design No. 320, Three Servicemen, 1943 (Box 1)
      [Give 'Em a Lift...Send a Gift!]
    - Design No. 321, Little Girl Praying, 1943 (Box 1)
      [...and Please...May There Always Be a Christmas]
    - Design No. 322, Christmas Holly, 1943 (Box 1)
      [Christmas...The Promise of Permanent Peace]
  - Civilian Defense - Auxiliary Organizations
    - Design No. 315, United States Civilian Defense Corps, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      [We Salute the United States Civilian Defense Corps]
    - Design No. 316, Air Raid Warden, 1943 (Box 1)
      [We Salute the Air Raid Wardens]
    - Design No. 317, Auxiliary Policeman, 1943 (Box 1)
      [It's an Honor and Distinction to Be Active in Civilian Defense]
    - Design No. 318, Auxiliary Fireman and Fire Watchers, 1943 (Box 1)
      [Reliable Men of Ability and Stamina...]
  - Miscellaneous Designs
    - American Red Cross Design No. 2 - Blood Donor, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      [Wounded Soldier - Your Blood Can Save Him!]
    - U.S. Women's Army Corps (WAC), Design No. 2, 1944 (Box 1)
      [I'd Rather Be With Them - Than Waiting]
    - Design No. 314, Church, 1943 (Box 1)
      [Where the Church Has Been Forgotten...Civilization Has Been Lost!]
    - Unnumbered Design, Flag, 1942 (Box 1)
      [Buy U.S. War Savings Bonds and Stamps Now]
    - Unnumbered Design, Woman Shopper, circa 1944 (Box 1)
      [Keep Down Your Cost of Living - Carry the Official Food Price List...]
    - Unnumbered Design, Stars, circa 1945 (Box 1)
      [Work for Victory - Save for Tomorrow - Buy Defense Bonds and Stamps]
  - National Housing Administration
    - Design No. 1, Welcome Mat, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      [Share Your Home with a War Worker's Family]
    - Design No. 2, House, 1943 (Box 1)
      [Make a Home for a War Worker's Family]
    - Design No. 3, Fatherless Family, 1944 (Box 1)
      [Daddy's a War Worker...Share Your Home with Us]
  - Office of Civilian Defense
    - Design No. 1, Volunteer Fireman, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      [Let 'Em Come...'V' Homes are Ready!]
    - Design No. 2, Policeman, 1943 (Box 1)
      ['Tis a Fine, Patriotic Thing to Do' - Share Your Car - a 'V' Home Does]
    - Design No. 3, Distraught Woman, 1943 (Box 1)
      [...Missing in Action...Somebody Talked - 'V' Homes are Careful]
    - Design No. 5, Home Canning, 1943 (Box 1)
      [Add to Your Ration - By Home Canning!]
    - Design No. 6, Life Raft, 1943 (Box 1)
      [What Did You Do Today for Freedom?]
    - Design No. 7, Tank, 1943 (Box 1)
      [We Can't Do It All]
    - Design No. 8, Nurse, 1943 (Box 1)
      [Your Job is Important Too]
    - Design No. 9, Marine, 1943 (Box 1)
      [The More You Help, the Quicker I'll Be Back]
  - Office of War Information
    - Design No. 1, Soldier with Gun, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      [Get into the Fight! Help Harvest War Crops]
    - Design No. 2, Newspaper Headline, 1944 (Box 1)
      [Crop Emergency Here!]
  - U.S. Department of Agriculture (Box 2)
    - Design No. 1, Forest Fire Poster, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      [Timber is Vital to War Effort!]
    - Design No. 2, Forest Fire, 1944 (Box 2)
      [Watch Your Cigarette]
    - Design No. 3, Forest Fire, 1944 (Box 2)
      [What Fire Destroys is Never Recovered]
    - Design No. 4, Four Bears, 1945 (Box 2)
      [Prevent Forest Fires]
  - U.S. Navy - WAVES
    - Design No. 2, WAVE and Sailors, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      [They Need You...Help Them Win - Enlist in the WAVES]
    - Design No. 3, Proud Family, 1944 (Box 2)
      [It's a Grand Glorious Feeling! Enlist in the WAVES]
    - Design No. 4, Parachute Rigger, 1944 (Box 2)
      [Have You Got What It Takes...]
    - Unnumbered Design, Mother and Daughter, 1944 (Box 2)
      [He'll Be Home Sooner...Now, You've Joined the WAVES]
  - U.S. Treasury Department
    - Design No. 9, Torpedo - War Bond Quota Campaign, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      [10 Per Cent in War Bonds]
    - Design No. 10, Tank - War Bond Quota Campaign, 1942 (Box 2)
    - Design No. 11, Cannon - War Bond Quota Campaign, 1942 (Box 2)
      [At Least 10 Per Cent in War Bonds]
    - Design No. 13, Airplane - War Bond Quota Campaign, 1942 (Box 2)
      [Invest At Least 10 Per Cent in War Bonds]
    - Design No. 14, Merchant Marines - War Bond Quota Campaign, 1942 (Box 2)
      [Invest At Least 10 Per Cent]
    - Design No. 15, Navy Anti-Aircraft Gunner - War Bond Quota Campaign, 1942 (Box 2)
      [Save At Least 10% in War Bonds]
    - Design No. 16, Army Anti-Aircraft Gunner - War Bond Quota Campaign, 1942 (Box 2)
    - Design No. 17, Flag - War Bond Quota Campaign, 1942 (Box 2)
      [To employees at... Congratulations on your pledge of 10% for War Bonds]
    - Design No. 18, P.T. Boat - War Bond Quota Campaign, 1942 (Box 2)
      [Save Every Pay Day At Least 10% in War Bonds]
    - Design No. 19, Marine Paratrooper - War Bond Quota Campaign, 1942 (Box 2)
      [Save Every PD At Least 10% in War Bonds]
    - Design No. 20, Top that 10% - War Bond Quota Campaign, 1942 (Box 2)
      [Buy War bonds - top that 10% by New Year's]
    - Design No. 21, Lincoln Memorial - War Bond Quota Campaign, 1943 (Box 2)
      [The Government of the people, by the people and for the people, shall not perish from Earth - Invest at least 10% in War Bonds]
    - Design No. 22, Do Your Best (Uncle Sam) - War Bond Quota Campaign, 1943 (Box 2)
      [You've Done Your Bit...Now Do Your Best]
    - Design No. 23, 2nd War Loan - War Bond Quota Campaign, 1943 (Box 2)
      [An Investment for Every Purse]
    - Design No. 24, Happy Family, 1943 (Box 2)
      [Buy War Bonds for Fighting Power Today...and Buying Power Tomorrow!]
    - Design No. 25, Blue Prints, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Design No. 26, Graduation, 1943 (Box 2)
    - Design No. 26, Invasion, 1943 (Box 2)
      [War Bonds in Action - Victory! Demands Continued Action]
    - Design No. 27, Soldiers, 1943 (Box 2)
      [Back the Attack]
    - Design No. 28, Planes in Action, 1943 (Box 2)
      [War Bonds in Action]
    - Design No. 29, Wedding, 1943 (Box 2)
      [Buy War Bonds for Fighting Power Today...and for Tomorrow's Brighter World]
    - Design No. 30, Pointing Finger, 1943 (Box 2)
      [Figure it Out Yourself - Boost Your Bond Buying Thru Payroll Savings]
    - Design No. 31, Tanks in Action, 1943 (Box 2)
      [War Bonds in Action!]
    - Design No. 33, Periscope View, 1943 (Box 2)
      [Let's All Back the Attack!]
    - Design No. 34, Let 'Em Have It!, 1944 (Box 2)
      [Let's All Back the Attack! - 4th War Loan]
    - Design No. 35, Crowd with Signs, 1944 (Box 2)
    - Design No. 36, Periscope, 1944 (Box 2)
      [Your War Bonds in Action]
    - Design No. 37, Aircraft Carrier, 1944 (Box 2)
    - Design No. 38, Soldier and Flag, 1944 (Box 2)
      [Buy War Bonds - To Have and to Hold!]
    - Design No. 39, Eagle, Sales Kit, 1944 (Box 2)
      [Back the Attack! - Buy More than Before - 5th War Loan]
    - Design No. 39, Eagle, 1944 (Box 2)
    - Design No. 40, Broom (Nazi Helmet and Flag), 1944 (Box 2)
      [Extra War Bonds - 5th War Loan]
    - Design No. 41, Eagle, Sales Kit, 1944 (Box 2)
      [Back the Attack! - Buy More than Before]
    - Design No. 41, Eagle, 1944 (Box 2)
    - Design No. 42, Advancing Soldiers, 1944 (Box 2)
      [Buy Extra Bonds for LIBERATION]
    - Design No. 47, 1944 (Box 2)
      [Hasten the Day! - Buy War Bonds]
    - Design No. 48, Pacific Fleet, Sales Kit, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      [There's No 7th Inning Stretch in Wartime]
    - Design No. 49, Shield, 1944 (Box 2)
      [My Thinking - My Money - My Time - 6th War Loan]
    - Design No. 50, Pilot, 1944 (Box 2)
      [At Least One Extra for the Sixth! - 6th War Loan]
    - Design No. 51, Liberty Bell and Christmas Decorations, 1944 (Box 2)
      [For Liberty and Peace on Earth]
    - Design No. 52, Fighting Bonds, 1944 (Box 2)
      [The War Bonds You Hold are Fighting Bonds!]
    - Design No. 53, Roll of Honor, 1944 (Box 2)
      [Your Country is Still at War - Are You?]
    - Design No. 54, Happy Investor, Black and White Sales Kit, 1945 (Box 2)
      [A Few More War Bonds Drives and I'll Be Set for Years]
    - Design No. 54, Happy Investor, Color Poster, 1945 (Box 2)
    - Design Nos. 55, 56, 1945 [on one poster sheet] (Box 3, Folder 12)
      [No. 55, Workers, Plan Now for the Bigger 7th War Loan; no. 56, Soldiers, The Bond Between Us - 7th War Loan]
    - Design No. 57, Workers, 1945 (Box 3)
      [Stay On the Job - Buy War Bonds - 7th War Loan]
    - Design No. 58, Iwo Jima, Sales Kit, 1945 (Box 3)
      [Keep It Up! ...Buy More War Bonds]
    - Design No. 59, War Bond, 1945 (Box 3)
      [...For Your Security and Mine...Buy and Hold War Bonds]
    - Design No. 60, Soldier on Stretcher, 1945 (Box 3)
      [Help Him Get Well - Buy Bonds]
    - Design No. 61, Happy Investor, 1945 (Box 3)
      [I Buy 'Em Now...and Will Keep On Buying Thru Payroll Savings]
    - Design No. 62, Victory Loan, Sales Kit, 1945 (Box 3)
      [They've Finished Their Job - Let's Finish Ours]
    - Design No. 63, Three Wise Men, Sales Kit, 1945 (Box 3)
      [For Peace and Security - Buy Bonds]
    - Design Nos. 62, 63, 1945 [on one poster sheet] (Box 3)
      [No. 62, Victory Loan; no. 63 Three Wise Men]
    - Design Nos. 43, 44, 45, Sales Kit, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 13)
      [No. 43 Working Man, no. 44, Crowd with Banners; no. 45, We Can't Do It All]
    - Design Nos. 49, 50, 51, Sales Kit - 6th War Loan - Vital to Victory, 1944 (Box 3)
      [No. 49, Shield; no. 50, Pilot; no. 51, Liberty Bell and Christmas Decorations]
    - Design Nos. 54, 62, Sales Kit, Buy and Hold War Bonds, 1945 (Box 3)
      [No. 54, Happy Investor; no. 62, Victory Loan]
    - Design Nos. 55, 56, 57, Sales Kit, 7th War Loan - Get Set America!, 1945 (Box 3)
      [No. 55, Plan Now; no. 56, Bond Between Us; no. 57 Stay on the Job]
    - Design Nos. 55, 56, 57, Sales Kit, Hit 'Em Again - Harder than Ever, 1945 (Box 3)
    - Unnumbered Design, Treasury Dept. Promotional Materials, circa 1943 (Box 3)
      [Back the Attack - 3rd War Loan]
  - War Food Administration
    - Design No. 1, Woman, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 14)
      [Produce, Conserve, Share, Play Square with Food!]
    - Design No. 2, Food Basket, 1943 (Box 3)
      [Food Fights for Freedom - To Hasten War's End!]
    - Design No. 3, Hungry Child and Soldier, 1944 (Box 3)
      [Food Wins Victories - Play Square with It]
    - Design No. 4, Smiling Grocer, 1944 (Box 3)
      [Help Him When You Shop]
    - Design No. 5, Victory Garden, 1944 (Box 3)
      [Victory Gardens - More for Them - More for You]
    - Design No. 6, Home Front Pledge, 1944 (Box 3)
      [Pay No More than Ceiling Prices - Pay Your Points in Full]
    - Design No. 7, Children Playing Grownups, 1944 (Box 3)
      [Stretch Your Ration Points]
  - War Manpower Commission
    - Design No. 1, Soldier, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 15)
      [Get a War Job to Help Him Fight]
    - Design No. 2, Uncle Sam, 1943 (Box 3)
      [Man Those Idle Machines]
    - Design No. 3, Uncle Sam (James Montgomery Flagg, artist) 1943 (Box 3)
      [Are You in a War Job?...If not, see U.S. Employment Service]
    - Design No. 4, Women at Work, 1943 (Box 3)
      [The More Women at Work the Sooner We Win]
    - Design No. 7, Metal Miner, 1944 (Box 3)
      [Fighting Men Need Fighting Metal! ...Thousands More Miners Needed!]
    - Design No. 9, Three Hands, 1944 (Box 3)
      [Let's Work - Not Wait for Victory]
    - Design No. 11, Grandma, 1944 (Box 3)
      [Women are Needed NOW for War Work and Essential Civilian Jobs]
    - Design No. 12, Whistle, 1944 (Box 3)
      [America at War Needs You at Work!]
    - Design No. 19, Girl War Worker, 1944 (Box 3)
      [Let's All Work - Not Wait for Victory]
    - Unnumbered Design, Uncle Sam, circa 1944 (Box 3)
      [Your Job Should Be a War Job]
- War Effort Sample Posters Series, 1942-1945, 2 boxes
  Arranged alphabetically by the government agency or other client represented in the advertisements, and thereunder by design number which was printed on the verso of most posters. Unnumbered posters are listed at the end of each group, and are noted as being unnumbered. If there is more than one unnumbered design poster at the end of a group, they are arranged chronologically.
  - Christmas Designs (Box 4)
    - Design No. 321, Little Girl Praying, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Unnumbered Design, Sales Kit, 1943 (Box 4)
  - Civilian Defense - Auxiliary Organizations
    - Design No. 315, United States Civilian Defense Corps, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Design No. 316, Air Raid Warden, 1943 (Box 4)
    - Design No. 317, Auxiliary Policeman, 1943 (Box 4)
    - Design No. 318, Auxiliary Fireman and Fire Watchers, 1943 (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous Designs
    - American Red Cross Design No. 2 - Blood Donor, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - American Red Cross, Unnumbered Design, circa 1944 (Box 4)
      [Give From Your Heart]
    - U.S. Women's Army Corps (WAC), Design No. 2, 1944 (Box 4)
    - Design No. 299, Orchid, 1943 (Box 4)
    - Design No. 314, Church, 1943 (Box 4)
    - Unnumbered Design, National Association of Manufacturers (NAM), circa 1943 (Box 4)
  - National Housing Administration
    - Design No. 1, Welcome Mat, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Design No. 2, House, 1943 (Box 4)
    - Design No. 3, Fatherless Family, 1944 (Box 4)
  - Office of Civilian Defense
    - Design No. 2, Policeman, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Design No. 3, Distraught Woman, 1943 (Box 4)
    - Design No. 4, Victory Gardens, Black and White Poster, 1943 (Box 4)
      [Victory Gardens...More for them...more for you]
    - Design No. 5, Home Canning, 1943 (Box 4)
    - Design No. 6, Life Raft, 1943 (Box 4)
    - Design No. 8, Nurse, 1943 (Box 4)
  - Office of War Information
    - Design No. 1, Soldier with Gun, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Design No. 2, Newspaper Headline, 1944 (Box 4)
  - U.S. Department of Agriculture
    - Design No. 1, Forest Fire Poster, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Design No. 2, Forest Fire, 1944 (Box 4)
    - Design No. 3, Forest Fire, 1944 (Box 4)
  - U.S. Navy - WAVES
    - Design No. 2, WAVE and Sailors, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Design No. 3, Proud Family, 1944 (Box 4)
    - Unnumbered Design, Mother and Daughter, 1944 (Box 4)
  - U.S. Treasury Department (Box 5)
    - War Bonds (Folder 1 of 2) (Folder 24)
      - Design No. 11, Cannon - War Bond Quota Campaign, 1942 (Box 5)
      - Design No. 16, Army Anti-Aircraft Gunner - War Bond Quota Campaign, 1942 (Box 5)
      - Design No. 17, Flag - War Bond Quota Campaign, 1942 (Box 5)
      - Design No. 20A, Top that 10% - War Bond Quota Campaign, 1942 (Box 5)
        [Buy War Bonds - Top That 10% Everybody Every Payday]
      - Design No. 21, Lincoln Memorial - War Bond Quota Campaign, 1943 (Box 5)
      - Design No. 22, Do Your Best (Uncle Sam) - War Bond Quota Campaign, 1943 (Box 5)
      - Design No. 24, Happy Family, 1943 (Box 5)
      - Design No. 25, Blue Prints, 1943 (Box 5)
      - Design No. 26, Graduation, 1943 (Box 5)
      - Design No. 29, Wedding, 1943 (Box 5)
      - Design No. 30, Pointing Finger, 1943 (Box 5)
      - Design No. 31, Tanks in Action, 1943 (Box 5)
      - Design No. 36, Periscope, 1944 (Box 5)
      - Design No. 37, Aircraft Carrier, 1944 (Box 5)
    - War Bonds (Folder 2 of 2) (Folder 25)
      - Design No. 38, Soldier and Flag, 1944 (Box 5)
      - Design No. 41, Eagle, 1944 (Box 5)
      - Design No. 42, Advancing Soldiers, 1944 (Box 5)
      - Design No. 48, Pacific Fleet, Sales Kit, 1944 (Box 5)
        [Keep Backing the Attack]
      - Design No. 51, Liberty Bell and Christmas Decorations, 1944 (Box 5)
      - Design No. 52, Fighting Bonds, 1944 (Box 5)
      - Design No. 53, Roll of Honor, 1944 (Box 5)
      - Design No. 54, Happy Investor, Black and White Sales Kit, 1945 (Box 5)
      - Design No. 54, Happy Investor, Black and White Poster, 1945 (Box 5)
      - Design No. 58, Iwo Jima, Sales Kit, 1945 (Box 5)
      - Unnumbered Design, Treasury Dept. Promotional Materials, 1942 (Box 5)
        [We Can, We Will, We Must (Franklin D. Roosevelt) Buy U.S. Savings Bonds and Stamps]
    - 2nd War Loan (Folder 26)
      - Design No. 23, 2nd War Loan - War Bond Quota Campaign, 1943 (Box 5)
    - 3rd War Loan (Folder 27)
      - Design No. 27, Soldiers, 1943 (Box 5)
    - 4th War Loan (Folder 28)
      - Design No. 33, Periscope View, 1943 (Box 5)
      - Design No. 34, Let 'Em Have It!, 1944 (Box 5)
      - Design No. 35, Crowd with Signs, 1944 (Box 5)
    - 5th War Loan (Folder 29)
      - Design No. 39, Eagle, 1944 (Box 5)
      - Design No. 40, Broom (Nazi Helmet and Flag), 1944 (Box 5)
    - 6th War Loan (Folder 30)
      - Design No. 49, Shield, 1944 (Box 5)
      - Design No. 50, Pilot, 1944 (Box 5)
  - War Food Administration
    - Design No. 1, Woman, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Design No. 2, Food Basket, 1943 (Box 5)
    - Design No. 3, Hungry Child and Soldier, 1944 (Box 5)
    - Design No. 4, Smiling Grocer, 1944 (Box 5)
    - Design No. 5, Victory Garden, 1944 (Box 5)
    - Design No. 6, Home Front Pledge, 1944 (Box 5)
    - Design No. 7, Children Playing Grownups, 1944 (Box 5)
    - Unnumbered Design, Woman Shopper, circa 1943 (Box 5)
      [Keep Down Your Cost of Living: Carry the Official Food Price List...Never Pay More Than the Legal Price]
  - War Manpower Commission
    - Design No. 1, Soldier, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Design No. 2, Uncle Sam, 1943 (Box 5)
    - Design No. 3, Uncle Sam (James Montgomery Flagg, artist) 1943 (Box 5)
      [Are You in a War Job? ...If not, see U.S. Employment Service]
    - Design No. 4, Women at Work, 1943 (Box 5)
    - Design No. 5, Uncle Sam - War Job, Sales Kit, 1943 (Box 5)
    - Design No. 7, Metal Miner, 1944 (Box 5)
    - Design No. 7, Coal Miner, 1944 (Box 5)
      [Coal is Fighting Power! ...Thousands More Miners Needed!]
    - Design No. 9, Three Hands, 1944 (Box 5)
    - Design No. 10, Girl War Worker, 1944 (Box 5)
    - Design No. 11, Grandma, 1944 (Box 5)
    - Design No. 11, Grandma, Sales Kit, 1944 (Box 5)